{
  "Grade_5": [
    null,
    {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": 0,
      "question": "Which list of numbers is ordered from least to greatest?",
      "optA": "0.8, 3/5, 7/10",
      "optB": "7/10, 3/5, 0.8",
      "optC": "3/5, 7/10, 0.8",
      "optD": "0.8, 7/10, 3/5",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "To compare fractions and decimals, we must convert all of them to the same form. Since we already have two fractions, we can just convert 0.8 to a fraction. 0.8 can be written as 8/10, and this is the form we want in since we need a common denominator in order to compare fractions. 3/5 can be written as 6/10 if the numerator and denominator are multiplied by 2. Now we have 8/10, 6/10, and 7,10. From here we see that 6/10 is the smallest, followed by 7/10, and lastly, 8,10. Therefore, the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which fraction is equivalent to to 0.75?",
      "optA": "3/4",
      "optB": "4/5",
      "optC": "7/10",
      "optD": "7/5",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "0.75 can be represented as 75/100. Simplifying the fraction by dividing by 25 on the top and bottom, 75/100 turns into 3/4. So, the correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which decimal is equivalent to 3/10?",
      "optA": "0.6",
      "optB": "0.35",
      "optC": "3.0",
      "optD": "0.3",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "A denominator of 10 tells us that the number is the in the tenths place, so the decimal is 0.3. That corresponds with the answer choice D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "561.3 ÷ 3 = ?",
      "optA": null,
      "optB": null,
      "optC": null,
      "optD": null,
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "187.1",
      "explanation": "Therefore, the answer is 187.1.",
      "explanationPicNumber": 0
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": 1,
      "question": "What is the remainder after long division is performed?",
      "optA": "1",
      "optB": "2",
      "optC": "3",
      "optD": "4",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "Therefore, the remainder is 1.",
      "explanationPicNumber": 1
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": 2,
      "question": "A bakery has 5 apple pies to serve. The chart below shows the orders of pies from customers. How much pie will be left after the orders are completed?",
      "optA": "3",
      "optB": "2 11/12",
      "optC": "1 5/12",
      "optD": "2 5/12",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "Adding up Millie and Fred’s orders- 9/12 + 16/12 = 25/12. Adding that with Eric’s order- 25/12 + 3/2 = 25/12 +18/12 = 43/12 = 3+7/12 pies. 5 - 3+7/12 = 1 + 5/12 pies. So, the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": 3,
      "question": "Kaycee went to the candy store and bought 11 pounds of jellybeans. This chart shows the amount she bought of each flavor. How many pounds of grape jelly beans did Kaycee buy?",
      "optA": null,
      "optB": null,
      "optC": null,
      "optD": null,
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "3.4 pounds",
      "explanation": "Since Kaycee bought 11 pounds of Jelly Beans total, the weight of the three flavors she bought should add up to 11 pounds. Lemon and Blueberry: 4.7+2.9 = 7.6. So, the weight of the grape jelly beans is 11-7.6 = 3.4 pounds.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": 4,
      "question": "Compute the equation.",
      "optA": "17.28",
      "optB": "16.308",
      "optC": "15.308",
      "optD": "18.28",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "We set up the problem ignoring the decimal points at first. We put 302 on top, as it is the longer number. At the end, we count up the numbers after the decimal point and add them to find where the decimal point will be in our answer. 3.02 has two digits after the decimal point and 5.4 has one. 1+2= 3, so there are three digits after the decimal point, making our answer 16.308. Therefore, the correct answer choice is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": 2
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which of the following fractions is equivalent to 0.35?",
      "optA": "7/20",
      "optB": "7/50",
      "optC": "35/50",
      "optD": "35/10",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "0.35 is equal to 35/100 since the digits after the decimal place reach the hundredths place. After simplifying the fraction by dividing the top and bottom by 5, the fraction becomes 7/20. So, the correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Jason and Patricia work in the same company. Jason earned $56,134 last year while Patricia earned $67,331. How much more money did Patricia make than Jason?",
      "optA": "$10,197",
      "optB": "$13,124",
      "optC": "$11,197",
      "optD": "$12,327",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "To find how much more money Patricia made than Jason, we can just subtract the amount Patricia made from the amount Jason made.",
      "explanationPicNumber": 3
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "543/30",
      "optA": "17",
      "optB": "18",
      "optC": "17 R3",
      "optD": "18 R3",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "",
      "explanationPicNumber": 4
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which measurement is closest to the amount of orange juice in one glass?",
      "optA": "2 cups",
      "optB": "2 pints",
      "optC": "2 liters",
      "optD": "2 gallons",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "A cup is the most reasonable measurement in this case. Two pints, two liters, and two gallons would not fit in a regular drinking glass.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 5,
      "question": "The measurement tool shown could be used to identify the—",
      "optA": "Weight of an object",
      "optB": "Length of an object.",
      "optC": "Measure of an angle",
      "optD": "Time elapsed",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "The measurement tool shown above is a protractor. These are used to measure angles. Therefore, the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "What measurement would Farmer Joe have to use to determine how much space he has to plant corn?",
      "optA": "Perimeter",
      "optB": "Area",
      "optC": "Volume",
      "optD": "Height",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "Area is used to measure surfaces like a piece of land, making it the reasonable measurement in this case. So, answer choice B is the correct answer.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 6,
      "question": "What is shown in the picture of the circle?",
      "optA": "Radius",
      "optB": "Diameter",
      "optC": "Chord",
      "optD": "Circumference",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "The line that touches the two sides of the circle and goes through the center point of the circle is the diameter. So, the correct answer is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 7,
      "question": "What is shown in the picture of the circle?",
      "optA": "Radius",
      "optB": "Diameter",
      "optC": "Chord",
      "optD": "Circumference",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "The line that has one point on the circle and the other at the center point is the radius. So, the correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 8,
      "question": "What is shown in the picture of the circle?",
      "optA": "Radius",
      "optB": "Diameter",
      "optC": "Chord",
      "optD": "Circumference",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "A chord of a circle is a straight line segment whose endpoints both lie on the circle. That is what the circle in the image above shows. Therefore, the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "What is the perimeter of a circle called?",
      "optA": "Radius",
      "optB": "Diameter",
      "optC": "Chord",
      "optD": "Circumference",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "The perimeter of a circle is called the circumference. So, the correct answer is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "What is 3456.27 rounded to the nearest whole number?",
      "optA": null,
      "optB": null,
      "optC": null,
      "optD": null,
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "3256",
      "explanation": "0.27 is less than 0.5 so it gets rounded down to zero. Therefore the answer is just 3456.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which of the following digits could be found in the ones digit of a number that is divisible by 2?",
      "optA": "0",
      "optB": "1",
      "optC": "3",
      "optD": "5",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "A number divisible by two is an even number. This means the ones digit must be also divisible by two. 1,3, and 5 are never divisible by 2. However, 0 is an even number, and numbers like 10, 20, 30 are divisible by two. So, the correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": 9,
      "question": "Based on the order of operations, compute the expression.",
      "optA": "10",
      "optB": "8",
      "optC": "6",
      "optD": "5",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "Applying the order of operations, multiplication and division must be done before addition and subtraction. So the expression turns into 4+(8*2/4). Computing from left to right, we get 4+(16/4) which is just 4+4 = 8. Therefore, the correct answer is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": 10,
      "question": "Based on the order of operations, compute the expression.",
      "optA": "4",
      "optB": "16",
      "optC": "2",
      "optD": "1",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "By the order of operations, PEMDAS, the (5+3) must be evaluated first. Then that gives 8/2-1*2. We do multiplication and division before subtraction so by doing those, we get 4-2 = 2. Therefore, the answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which of the following numbers is divisible by 3?",
      "optA": "434",
      "optB": "551",
      "optC": "814",
      "optD": "525",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "To see if a number is divisible by 3, we can add up the digits and check if the sum of the digits is divisible by 3. For A, 4+3+4 = 11 which is not divisible by 3. For B, 5+5+1 is also 11 which is not divisible by 3. For C, 8+1+4 = 13 which is not divisible by 3. For D, 5+2+5 = 12 which is divisible by 3. Therefore, 525 is divisible by three and D is the correct answer.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which one of these numbers is a prime number?",
      "optA": "81",
      "optB": "75",
      "optC": "51",
      "optD": "23",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "A prime number has no other factors except for 1 and itself. A is not correct, 81 is not prime, it is divisible by 3, 9, and 27. B is not correct, 75 is divisible by 5 and 25. C is not correct, though it seems like it might be a prime number, it is divisible by 3 and 17. D is correct, 23 is prime, as it has no other factors but one and itself.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which of these lists only contains odd numbers?",
      "optA": "5, 7, 11, 32",
      "optB": "3, 13, 15, 21",
      "optC": "4, 6, 10, 16",
      "optD": "3, 13, 16, 23",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "Odd numbers are not divisible by 2. A is incorrect because 32 is divisible by 2. In B, none of the numbers are divisible by 2, making it the correct answer. C is incorrect because it lists all even numbers instead. D is incorrect since it contains 16, which is divisible by 2.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "What is 342.1847 rounded to the nearest thousandths?",
      "optA": "342.186",
      "optB": "342.184",
      "optC": "342.187",
      "optD": "342.185",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "The thousandths place is the third digit after the decimal point, so we look at the fourth digit in order to round. The fourth digit is 7, which means the thousandths place gets rounded up. Therefore 342.1847 gets rounded to 342.185. So, the answer is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Computation and Estimation",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Buying a slice of pizza from Pete’s diner costs $2.35, and buying a burger costs $6.20. Jack buys 3 slices of pizza and 4 burgers from Pete’s diner. How much should he pay?",
      "optA": "$30.85",
      "optB": "$32.75",
      "optC": "$31.85",
      "optD": "$32.30",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "Jack buys 3 slices of pizza which will cost him 2.35 * 3 = 7.05. The 4 burgers will cost him 4* 6.20 = 24.8. Adding the costs of the pizza and burgers: 7.05+24.8= 31.85, so the answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Number and Number Sense",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which of these expressions is true?",
      "optA": "3.29 > 3.3",
      "optB": "3.29 < 3.209",
      "optC": "3.209 > 3.3",
      "optD": "3.29 > 3.209",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "When comparing decimals, look first at the tenths place, then hundredths and so on. In answer choice A, looking at the tenths place, the expression becomes false. In answer choice B, the tenths place is the same, but in the hundredths place, the expression becomes false. Same goes for answer choice c, the tenths place shows that the expression is false. Only in answer choice D are the values compared correctly.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "What is the area of a rectangle with a length of 8 and a width of 4?",
      "optA": "32",
      "optB": "24",
      "optC": "30",
      "optD": "100",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "The area of a rectangle is length times width. So in this case the area is just 4*8 = 32. Therefore, the correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "What is the volume of a cube with side length 5?",
      "optA": null,
      "optB": null,
      "optC": null,
      "optD": null,
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "125",
      "explanation": "The volume of a cube is l^3. 5 x 5 x 5 = 125.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 11,
      "question": "A regular hexagon has 6 sides with the same measurement. If one if the sides had a length of 5cm, what would the perimeter of the hexagon be?",
      "optA": null,
      "optB": null,
      "optC": null,
      "optD": null,
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "30 cm",
      "explanation": "Since each of the sides has length 5, and there are six sides, to total up all the sides we would do 5 x 6 = 30.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 12,
      "question": "Jerry wants to enclose his yard, which is shaped like an equilateral triangle, in fencing. The side length of his yard is 18 feet. How much fencing should he buy?",
      "optA": "54 feet",
      "optB": "64 feet",
      "optC": "32 feet",
      "optD": "144 feet",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "To figure out how much fencing Jerry needs to buy, we have to find the perimeter of the triangle. We just add up all the sides, which are all 18ft since it is an equilateral triangle. 18 x 3 = 54, therefore A is the correct answer.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "830 milliliters = ? liter(s)",
      "optA": ".0083",
      "optB": ".083",
      "optC": ".83",
      "optD": "8.3",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "There are 1000 milliliters in a liter. This means to convert from milliliters to liters, we must divide by 1000, or in other words, move the decimal place over three times to the left. That gives us 0.83, so C is the correct answer.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "1100 millimeters = ? meter(s)",
      "optA": "1.1",
      "optB": ".11",
      "optC": ".011",
      "optD": ".0011",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "There are 1000 millimeters in a meter. This means to convert from millimeters to meters, we must divide by 1000, or in other words, move the decimal place over three times to the left. That gives us 1.1, so A is the correct answer.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 13,
      "question": "What kind of angle is being shown in the image?",
      "optA": "Acute",
      "optB": "Right",
      "optC": "Obtuse",
      "optD": "Straight",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "The angle has a degree measure less than 90 degrees. Therefore, it is an acute angle, and the correct answer choice is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 14,
      "question": "What kind of angle is being shown in the image?",
      "optA": "Acute",
      "optB": "Right",
      "optC": "Obtuse",
      "optD": "Straight",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "The angle has a degree measure equal to 90 degrees. Therefore, it is a right angle, and the correct answer choice is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 15,
      "question": "What kind of angle is being shown in the image?",
      "optA": "Acute",
      "optB": "Right",
      "optC": "Obtuse",
      "optD": "Straight",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "The angle has a degree measure greater than 90 degrees. Therefore, it is an obtuse angle, and the correct answer choice is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": 16,
      "question": "The clock depicted shows the start time of a movie. If the movie is 2 hours and 10 minutes long, when will it end?",
      "optA": "8:40",
      "optB": "9:00",
      "optC": "9:40",
      "optD": "10:00",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "The current time is 7:30 so we must find what time it is 2 hour and 10 minutes later. 2 hours later, it will be 9:30, and another 10  minutes later it will be 9:40. Therefore, the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Measurement",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "A rectangular prism has a width of 3cm, the length is twice the width, and the height is 10cm. What is the volume of the rectangular prism?",
      "optA": "90cm^3",
      "optB": "120cm^3",
      "optC": "180cm^3",
      "optD": "270cm^3",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "The formula for the volume of a rectangular prism is length*width*height. The length of the rectangular is 6, width is 3, and height is 10. 6*3*10 = 180, so the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 17,
      "question": "What kind of angle is being shown in the image?",
      "optA": "Acute",
      "optB": "Right",
      "optC": "Obtuse",
      "optD": "Straight",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "The angle has a degree measure of 180 degrees. Therefore, it is a straight angle, and the correct answer choice is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "A quadrilateral has the following characteristics: Two pairs of parallel sides, two pairs of congruent opposite angles, two pairs of congruent opposite sides, and no right angles. Which of the following could it be?",
      "optA": "Square",
      "optB": "Parallelogram",
      "optC": "Rectangle",
      "optD": "Trapezoid",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "Looking at the answer choices, we immediately eliminate the square and rectangle since there are no right angles. With just the trapezoid and parallelogram left, the figure has two pairs of congruent opposite sides, and two pairs of parallel sides so if must be a parallelogram.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 18,
      "question": "What type of triangle is depicted?",
      "optA": "Equilateral",
      "optB": "Isosceles",
      "optC": "Scalene",
      "optD": "Right",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "It appears that all the sides are equal in length by inspection, so it must be an equilateral triangle. The correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 19,
      "question": "What type of triangle is depicted?",
      "optA": "Equilateral",
      "optB": "Isosceles",
      "optC": "Scalene",
      "optD": "Right",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "The triangle depicted has two sides that are equal, and one shorter side as the base, so it is an isosceles triangle. The correct answer is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 20,
      "question": "What type of triangle is depicted?",
      "optA": "Equilateral",
      "optB": "Isosceles",
      "optC": "Scalene",
      "optD": "Right",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "The triangle depicted has a ninety degree angle which is shown by the square, so it is a right triangle. The correct answer is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Geometry",
      "questionPicNumber": 21,
      "question": "What type of triangle is depicted?",
      "optA": "Equilateral",
      "optB": "Isosceles",
      "optC": "Scalene",
      "optD": "Right",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "In the triangle depicted, all the sides have different lengths, so it is a scalene triangle. The correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 22,
      "question": "Michael has two bags containing balls of certain colors. Bag A has 4 balls, Bag B has 2 balls. The colors of the balls are shown in the chart. Which of the following lists shows all the possible combinations of one block from each bag?",
      "optA": null,
      "optB": null,
      "optC": null,
      "optD": null,
      "optAPicNumber": 0,
      "optBPicNumber": 1,
      "optCPicNumber": 2,
      "optDPicNumber": 3,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "All the pairs are made from one color from each bag. So since there are no colors that overlap, B and D can be eliminated from the pairs like “Purple, Purple.” Looking at A and C, A is missing pairs because every color from bag A is not paired with both the colors in bag B. Therefore, the correct answer with all the pairs is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 23,
      "question": "The set of data shows how many hours Claudia slept each night for the past week. What is the median of the data set?",
      "optA": "5",
      "optB": "7",
      "optC": "8",
      "optD": "9",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "To find the median of a data set, we must sort the data from least to greatest: 5,7,7,8,8,9,9. From here we cross off the biggest and smallest digit until we reach the middle number. In our set, that number is 8. Therefore, the correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 24,
      "question": "The set of data shows how many cookies Sally ate in the past few days. What is the mean of the data set?",
      "optA": "6",
      "optB": "5",
      "optC": "3",
      "optD": "4",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "To find the mean, we first add up all the numbers in the data set, and then divide by the number of elements in the data set. The sum of all the numbers in our case is 20, and we have 5 elements. 20/5 = 4, so the answer is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 25,
      "question": "The set of data shows how many tests Eli took each day for the past week. What is the mode of the data set?",
      "optA": "2",
      "optB": "3",
      "optC": "4",
      "optD": "5",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "The mode is the element in a data set that appears the most times. In this data, 2 appears 3 times. No number appears the same or more number of times than the element 2, so it is the mode, and the correct answer choice is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 26,
      "question": "The set of data shows how many birds a bird watching group saw for the last couple of days. What is the range of the data set?",
      "optA": "19",
      "optB": "22",
      "optC": "15",
      "optD": "12",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "To find the range, subtract the smallest number in the data set from the greatest number. 31 is the greatest number in the data set and 9 is the smallest. 31 - 9 = 22, so the range is 22, and the correct answer choice is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 27,
      "question": "The stem-and-leaf plot shows some students’ test scores from their last exam. What is the most commonly scored score from the stem-and-leaf plot?",
      "optA": "77",
      "optB": "88",
      "optC": "91",
      "optD": "92",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "The most commonly scored score means we need to find the mode of the data set. The score that appears the most times in the data set is 88, so the correct answer choice is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 28,
      "question": "According to the graph, which is the best prediction for the number of DVDs that will be sold during week 7?",
      "optA": "700",
      "optB": "800",
      "optC": "900",
      "optD": "1000",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "The trend in the bar graph shows that each week the number of DVDs sold is increasing by 100. Week 7 is two weeks from week 5, and during week 5 700 DVDs were sold. So, it makes sense that week 7 sales would be 200 more than week 5. 700+200 = 900. The correct answer choice is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Probability and Statistics",
      "questionPicNumber": 29,
      "question": "A spinner with four equal sections is depicted. What is the probability that the arrow will land on blue?",
      "optA": "1/4",
      "optB": "1/2",
      "optC": "3/4",
      "optD": "4/4",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "Two out of the four of the sections are blue, so the probability of the pointer landing on blue is 2/4, or 1/2. The correct answer choice is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": 30,
      "question": "What numbers will fill in the pattern shown?",
      "optA": "22, 26",
      "optB": "21, 26",
      "optC": "21, 27",
      "optD": "22, 27",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "From the first three digits, we can tell that each term is five more than the last term. So as the pattern continues, each next term will be five more than the last one. The term after 17 will be 17+5 = 22. The term after that will be 22+5 = 27. Therefore, the correct answer is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": 31,
      "question": "What number will fill in the pattern shown?",
      "optA": "20",
      "optB": "50",
      "optC": "10",
      "optD": "25",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "The first two terms of the sequence have two possible relationships. The first is dividing by 5, since 500/5 = 100. The second is subtracting by 400. However, if the pattern was subtracting by 400 each time, the fourth term would be negative, but it’s not. So, the pattern must be dividing by 5. 100/5 = 20, and 20/5 = 4, so the pattern works. The correct answer is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Jamie bought 5 boxes of pencils. Each box had p number of pencils in it. Which equation can be used to determine how many pencils Jamie bought?",
      "optA": "5 + p",
      "optB": "5 - p",
      "optC": "5 x p",
      "optD": "5 / p",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "Since each box has p number of pencils. To find the amount of pencils Jamie bought in total, we would just do p+p+p+p+p which is just 5*p. The correct answer is C.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "A classroom is getting 3 new students. The variable y stands for the number of students in the original class. Which expression represents the class size with the three new students?",
      "optA": "y",
      "optB": "y + 3",
      "optC": "y x 3",
      "optD": "y - 3",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "b",
      "explanation": "The class had y amount of students, now three more joined, so the correct expression is y+3. The correct answer choice is B.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": 32,
      "question": "Miranda has 580 skittles that she wants to divide among 5 friends using the equation shown. What does x stand for in the equation?",
      "optA": "The number of friends receiving skittles",
      "optB": "The number of skittles Miranda has",
      "optC": "The number skittles remaining",
      "optD": "The number of skittles each friend gets",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "d",
      "explanation": "580 is the number of skittles Miranda has, and 5 is the number of friends Miranda is dividing her skittles between. So, 580/5 represents the number of skittles each friend gets. The correct answer is D.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": 33,
      "question": "Which problem could be solved by the expression shown?",
      "optA": "Ella ate 3 cookies a day for x number of days, the total number of cookies she ate was 12. For how many days did she eat 3 cookies?",
      "optB": "Ella ate 3 cookies a day for x number of days, how many cookies did she eat before she started counting?",
      "optC": "Ella ate 3 cookies a day for x number of days, how many cookies did she eat on Tuesday?",
      "optD": "Ella ate 3 cookies a day for x number of days, the total number of cookies she ate was 12. What cookie is her favorite?",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "a",
      "explanation": "We are given the fact that Ella ate 3 cookies a day for x number of days, the total number of cookies she ate was 12. So, we can solve for how many days she ate the 3 cookies until she reached 12. The correct answer choice is A.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }, {
      "category": "Patterns, Functions, and Algebra",
      "questionPicNumber": null,
      "question": "Which of the following choices shows distributive property?",
      "optA": "4+3 = 3+4",
      "optB": "4*0 = 0",
      "optC": "4(3+4) = 12+16",
      "optD": "4+0 = 4",
      "optAPicNumber": null,
      "optBPicNumber": null,
      "optCPicNumber": null,
      "optDPicNumber": null,
      "answer": "c",
      "explanation": "Answer choice A shows associative property. Answer choice B shows the zero product property of multiplication. Answer choice C shows the additive identity. Only answer choice D shows distributive property, correctly distributing the 4 to the two terms in the parentheses.",
      "explanationPicNumber": null
    }
  ]
}
